Guide to the Jane Howard Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Jane Howard Papers,
ca.1930-1996
Howard, Jane, 1935-
62 linear ft (ca. 60,000 items in 150 boxes & 6 card file boxes).
Columbia University Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Butler Library, New York, NY 10027.
4079538
Biographical Note
Jane Temple Howard (1935-1996), journalist and author, was born in Springfield, Illinois, the daughter of Eleanor Nee Howard and newspaper reporter Robert Pickerell Howard. She received her A.B. degree from the University of Michigan in 1956. She also received an honorary D.Litt. from Grinell College in 1979 and an honorary Doctor of Humane Letters from Hamline University in 1984. Howard worked for LIFE magazine from 1956 until 1972 as a reporter, assistant editor, associate editor, and finally staff writer. She wrote numerous features for LIFE including interviews with Vladimir Nabokov, Truman Capote, John Updike, and Jacqueline Susann. Beginning in 1989, she worked for several years at LEAR'S magazine as a contributing editor and author of the monthly interview column, "A Woman for LEAR'S." As a freelance writer, Howard contributed to SMITHSONIAN, ESQUIRE, THE WASHINGTON POST "BOOK WORLD", MADEMOISELLE, THE NEW YORK TIMES BOOK REVIEW, and numerous other publications. Howard's first book, PLEASE TOUCH: A GUIDED TOUR OF THE HUMAN POTENTIAL MOVEMENT was published in 1970. A DIFFERENT WOMAN appeared in 1973, FAMILIES in 1978, and the biography, MARGARET MEAD: A LIFE, in 1990. At the time of her death, Howard was writing a book under the working title LOST IN THE INTERIOR which was to be a personal and historical account of the midwest.
Also enjoying a successful teaching career, Howard was a visiting lecturer at the University of Iowa Writers' Workshop (Fall 1974), the University of Georgia School of Journalism (Spring 1975), Yale University English Department (Spring 1976), and the SUNY Albany English Department (Winter 1978). She was a John Steinbeck Writer-in-Residence at Southampton College (Summer 1982), and a James Thurber Writer-in Residence at Ohio State University (Fall 1986). During the summers of 1989 and 1990, Howard led non-fiction writing workshops at the Split Rock Arts Program at the University of Minnesota at Duluth. She was also a professor of creative writing at Columbia University for several years during the 1990s.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, manuscripts, drafts, notes, journals, scrapbooks, audio tapes, datebooks and calendars, photographs, printed material, and memorabilia. Included are files relating to articles which she researched and wrote while on the staff of LIFE magazine, especially on popular figures in current literature and the arts. There are also research files and typescripts for her books: PLEASE TOUCH, A DIFFERENT WOMAN, and FAMILIES. Among the correspondents are: Paul Bowles, Agnes de Mille, Ken Kesey, and Hope Cooke Namgyal.
ADDITION: Research files for FAMILIES & research files, typescripts, and note cards for MARGARET MEAD: A LIFE and unpublished manuscripts and related research files.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 20 series:
Series I: Cataloged Correspondence and Manuscripts
Series II: Life Magazine Articles
Series III: Books
Series IV: Miscellaneous Files
Series V: Note Cards
Series VI: 1989 Addition
Series VII: Correspondence
Series VIII: Writings
Series IX: Teaching Materials
Series X: Datebooks and Calendars
Series XI: Journals
Series XII: Memorabilia
Series XIII: Documents
Series XIV: Printed Material
Series XV: Topical Files
Seris XVI: Miscellaneous Files
Seris XVII: Audiotapes
Series XVIII: Scrapbooks
Series XIX: Photographs
Series XX: Addresses
Subjects
Life Magazine.; Bowles, Paul, 1910-1999.; Kesey, Ken.; Mead, Margaret, 1901-1978.; Journalism.; Popular culture.; Psychology.; Sociology.; Articles.; Card files.; Manuscripts for publication.; Notes.; Photoprints.; Authors, American--20th century.; Journalists--United States--20th century.; Women authors--United States--20th century.; Women journalists--United States--20th century.
Access Restrictions
This collection has no restrictions.
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material from the Rare Book and Manuscript Library at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
Acquisition
1979 M-1979 Howard, Jane Deposit
Deposited by Jane Howard, 1979, 1985, 1989, & 1996.
- Series I: Cataloged Correspondence and Manuscripts
  See also Box 53
  - Aiken, Conrad (Box 1)
  - Bowles, Paul (Box 1)
  - Chisholm, Shirley (Box 1)
  - Cowley, Malcolm (Box 1)
  - de Mille, Agnes George (Box 1)
  - Ford, Elizabeth Bloomer (Mrs. Gerald R.) (Box 1)
  - Kesey, Ken (Box 1)
  - Mannes, Marya (Box 1)
  - Marx, "Groucho' Julius (Box 1)
  - Maslow, Abraham (Box 1)
  - Micheline, Jack (Box 1)
  - Moore, Marianne C. (Box 1)
  - Namgyal, Hope Cooke (Box 1)
  - O'Hair, Madalyn E. Mays Murray (Box 1)
  - Stout, Rex Todhunter (Box 1)
  - Susann, Jacqueline (Box 1)
  - Tucker, Sophie (Box 1)
  - Updike, John (Box 1)
- Series II: Life Magazine Articles
  - Adler, Bill, 1967 (Box 1)
  - African Students (Box 1)
  - Aiken, Conrad On T.S. Eliot (Box 1)
  - Alcoholism and Women (Box 1)
  - Alpha Waves (Box 1)
  - Astrowives, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Atkinson, Brooks, 1959 (Box 1)
  - Baird, Bil and Cora, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Baldwin, James (Box 1)
  - Baskin, Leonard (Box 1)
  - Bayh, Marvella (Box 1)
  - Beard, James (Box 1)
  - Biofeedback (Box 1)
  - Blanding, Sarah G., 1962 (Box 1)
  - Bon Vivant Soup Chaos (Box 2)
  - Bowles, Jane and Paul, 1967 (Box 2)
  - Browning, John (Box 2)
  - Burns, Cathy (Box 2)
  - Calder, Alexander (Box 2)
  - Carson, Rachel (Box 2)
  - Child, Julia (Box 2)
  - Chisholm, Shirley (Box 2)
  - Churchill, Sarah (Box 2)
  - Cohen, Alexander (Box 2)
  - Curtin, Phyllis (Box 2)
  - Davis, Adele (Box 2)
  - deMille, Agnes, 1963 (Box 3)
  - Dennis, Patrick, 1963 (Box 3)
  - Dewhurst, Colleen, and George C. Scott, 1963 (Box 3)
  - Dixon, Jeane (Box 3)
  - Duke, Patty (Box 3)
  - Early Life Research, 1957- (Box 3)
  - Fielding, Temple, 1967 (Box 3)
  - Fischer, Bobby, 1962 (Box 3)
  - Free Schools (Box 4)
  - Friedan, Betty (Box 4)
  - Gezork - Stolen Earring, 1964 (Box 4)
  - Graves, Robert (Box 4)
  - Greene, Graham (Box 4)
  - Grost, Michael (kid genius), 1965 (Box 4)
  - Hall, Joyce (Box 4)
  - Hamilton, Lindsay, 1962 (Box 4)
  - Harris, Lou, 1962 (Box 4)
  - Hartford, Huntigton, 1962 (Box 5)
  - Heckscher, August, 1962 (Box 5)
  - Heloise Cruse (Box 5)
  - Hicks, Louise Day (Box 5)
  - Huston, John (Box 5)
  - Jacobs, Jane (Box 5)
  - Jesus Freaks of Rye, N.Y. (Box 5)
  - Keane, Walter (Box 6)
  - Kesey, Ken (Box 6)
  - Knopf, Alfred A. and Blanche (Box 6)
  - Knowles, Everett (Box 6)
  - LaVarre, Frank (Box 6)
  - Linowitz, Sol (Box 6)
  - Littlewood, Joan (Box 6)
  - Lowell, Robert (Box 6)
  - McGovern, Eleanor (Box 6)
  - McLuhan, Marshall (Box 7)
  - Mannes, Marya (Box 7)
  - Marx, Groucho (Box 7)
  - Masters, George (Box 7)
  - Miller, Jonathan, 1963 (Box 7)
  - Mind Control (Box 7)
  - Moffo, Anna, 1961 (Box 7)
  - Moore, Marianne, 1966 (Box 7)
  - Moses, Robert (Box 7)
  - Murphy, R.C, 1959 (Box 7)
  - Nabokov, [Vladimir] (Box 7)
  - Namgyal, Hope (Box 8)
  - Nepal (Box 8)
  - Niehans, Paul (Box 8)
  - Norman, Don Cleveland (Box 8)
  - Nudity (Box 8)
  - O'Brien, Edna (Box 8)
  - O'Hair, Madalyn Murray (Box 9)
  - Palley, Reese (Box 9)
  - Parachuting (Box 9)
  - Perelman, S.J. (Box 9)
  - Petzoldt, Paul (Box 9)
  - Pollution (Box 9)
  - Pornography (Box 9)
  - Pornography (Box 10)
  - Radziwill, Lee (Box 10)
  - Right-Wingers of Wakeman Sound (Box 10)
  - Rock, Dr. John (Box 10)
  - Rockefeller, Happy, 1963 (Box 10)
  - Rooks, Conrad (Box 10)
  - Roth, Henry (Box 10)
  - Royal Canadian Air Force Exercises (Box 10)
  - Rubenstein, Helena (Box 10)
  - Sirachik, Mr. and Mrs. Philip (Box 10)
  - Sartre, Jean-Paul (Box 10)
  - Schippers, Thomas (Box 11)
  - Schoenknecht, Walt (Box 11)
  - Seeger, Pete (Box 11)
  - Serebriakoff, Victor (Box 11)
  - Shahn, Ben (Box 11)
  - Silence (Box 11)
  - Skinner, B.F. (Box 11)
  - Southern, Terry (Box 11)
  - Spilhaus, Athelstan (Box 11)
  - Stanley, Kim (Box 11)
  - Styron, Rose (Box 11)
  - Sutherland, Joan (Box 11)
  - Swaggart, Jimmy (Box 11)
  - Swamis (Box 12)
  - Susann, Jacqueline (Box 12)
  - Tree, Marietta (Box 12)
  - Tucker, Sophie (Box 12)
  - Updike, John (Box 12)
  - Verdon, Gwen, and Bob Fosse (Box 12)
  - Wouk, Herman (Box 12)
  - Zimmerman, Isidore (Box 12)
- Series III: Books
  - Subseries III.1: A Different Woman
    Boxes 13 - 17, Files are arranged alphabetically
    - Babbs, Gretchen, Oregon (Box 13)
    - Boccaccio, Shirley, San Francisco (Box 13)
    - Bonnema, Janet, Colorado (Box 13)
    - Brown, Abigail, New York City (Box 13)
    - Carrera of Bank of America (Box 13)
    - Cheryl the Vagabond, El Salvador (Box 13)
    - Chicanas, of Tucson (Box 13)
    - Cussler, Margaret, Maryland (Box 13)
    - Devore vs. Hughes, Santa Monica (Box 13)
    - Emery, Linda Vs. Colorado Medical School (Box 13)
    - Feminism Abroad, or lack thereof (Box 13)
    - Goetz, Del Vs. Bank of America (Box 14)
    - Griffith, Blanche, West Virginia (Box 14)
    - Heyman, Abby Abortion film, New York City (Box 14)
    - Hope, Karol Single motherhood, Los Angeles (Box 14)
    - Jagerson, Todd Labor (Box 14)
    - Kesey, Ken Women, Oregon (Box 14)
    - Lanoue, Betty Vs. Bank of America (Box 14)
    - Lucero, Carol Junian analyst, San Francisco (Box 14)
    - McGaw, Audrey, San Diego (Box 14)
    - Metcalf, Genevra, Colorado (Box 14)
    - Milazzo, Lou Ann, Queens (Box 14)
    - Milwaukee Consciousness Raising Group (Box 14)
    - Mullins, Theresa (Box 14)
    - Petrinovich, Mary Birth Control Clinic, Ca1ifornia (Box 14)
    - Phillips, Barbara, and Katie Wells Vs. Bank of America (Box 14)
    - Roberts, Sylvia Itinerant lawyer (Box 15)
    - Roig, Mrs. Vs. New Orleans phone company (Box 15)
    - Ross, Mari, and Sandy Wetzel Vs. Liberty Mutual (Box 15)
    - Rothenberg, Sandra D.C. lawyer (Box 15)
    - Rothman, Lorraine Lesbian self-help, Los Angeles (Box 15)
    - Sadler Women & South (Box 15)
    - Scheper, Nancy Berkeley single mother (Box 15)
    - Scott, Jeanne Los Angeles YWCA (Box 15)
    - Simborski, Irene Vs. Continental Can (Box 15)
    - Smith, Orpha Vermont maple sugar (Box 15)
    - Tunstall, Cro, Norfolk, Va. (Box 15)
    - Van Velkinburgh, Doris California fisherperson (Box 15)
    - Wadsworth, Beverly Vs. F.N.C.B. (Box 15)
    - Witherill, Linda, New Hampshire cats (Box 15)
    - Geographical File: Alabama - Louisiana (Box 15)
    - Geographical File: Maine - Wyoming, (Fan Mail and Miscellaneous) (Box 16)
    - Typescript (Box 17)
  - Subseries III.2: Families
    Boxes 18 - 25, Files are arranged alphabetically
    - Abortions (Box 18)
    - Academic and Intellectual Families (Box 18)
    - Adoptions and Baby Sales (Box 18)
    - Advertising and Families (Box 18)
    - Anthropology (Box 18)
    - Arbitrary Extended Families (Box 18)
    - Aries (Box 18)
    - Arica (Box 18)
    - Artists (Box 18)
    - Attacks on Families (Box 18)
    - Benne (Box 18)
    - Black Families (Box 18)
    - Books on Families (Box 18)
    - Book Reviews and Quotes (Box 18)
    - Bowen, Murray (Box 19)
    - Businesses (Box 19)
    - Careys (Box 19)
    - Carlson & Friends (Box 19)
    - Carters and Politics (Box 19)
    - Cartoons (Box 19)
    - Chapman, Richard (and Hobbes) (Box 19)
    - Chicano Families (Box 19)
    - Collectives (Box 19)
    - Communes and Real Estate (Box 19)
    - Crimes (Box 19)
    - Day Care (Box 19)
    - Definitions of Family (Box 19)
    - Deliberately Childless Couples (Box 19)
    - Diseased Families (Box 19)
    - Divorce (Box 19)
    - East River Farm (Box 19)
    - Economics and Families (Box 19)
    - Editing Process (Box 20)
    - Elderly Primagravidas (Box 20)
    - Ethnicity (Box 20)
    - Extrauterine Conception (Box 20)
    - Families in General (Box 20)
    - Fathers (Box 20)
    - Family Reunions (Box 20)
    - Familyologists (Box 20)
    - Families of One (Box 20)
    - Families and Feminism (Box 21)
    - The Farm (Box 21)
    - Foreign Families (Box 21)
    - Foster Families (Box 21)
    - Gage & Greeks (Box 21)
    - Genealogy (Box 21)
    - Government vs Families (Box 21)
    - Grandparents (Box 21)
    - Green and Black Rocks (Box 21)
    - Heraldry (Box 21)
    - Hippies (Box 21)
    - History (Box 21)
    - Homosexuality (Box 22)
    - Housing (Box 22)
    - Hsu, Francis (Box 22)
    - Incest (Box 22)
    - Interracial Families (Box 22)
    - Iowa (Box 22)
    - Jargon (Box 22)
    - Jenkins, Gladys (Box 22)
    - Jewish Families (Box 22)
    - Jewish: Orbach-Cadein (Box 22)
    - Kearney/Raschke (Box 22)
    - Keniston (Box 22)
    - Kids (Box 22)
    - Laucks, Eulahh (Box 22)
    - Lesbian Mothers (Box 22)
    - Living in Sin (Box 22)
    - Male Supremacy (Box 22)
    - Marriage Contracts (Box 22)
    - Marriage, Couples, Sex (Box 22)
    - May-December Love (Box 22)
    - Medicine (Box 22)
    - Middle Age (Box 22)
    - Midwifery (Box 22)
    - Migrants (Box 22)
    - Military Families (Box 22)
    - Mobility (Box 23)
    - Morality (Box 23)
    - Mormons (Box 23)
    - Mothers (Box 23)
    - Movies (Box 23)
    - Muktananda (Box 23)
    - Multiple Births (Box 23)
    - Mythology (Box 23)
    - Narcissism (Box 23)
    - Networks (Box 23)
    - Nuns Marrying Priests (Box 23)
    - Pets (Box 23)
    - Polygamy (Box 23)
    - Poor Families (Box 23)
    - Retarded and Autistic Kids (Box 23)
    - Scrambling of Identities (Box 23)
    - Siblings (Box 23)
    - South (Box 23)
    - Statistics (Box 23)
    - Step-Families (Box 24)
    - Suicide (Box 24)
    - Swenson (Box 24)
    - Synergy (Box 24)
    - Tax, Sol (Box 24)
    - Teen Pregnancies (Box 24)
    - Television (Box 24)
    - Therapists (Box 24)
    - Transexual Families (Box 24)
    - Unitarians (Box 24)
    - Very Rich Families (Box 24)
    - Villains' Families (Box 24)
    - Wilderness Families (Box 24)
    - Winnowed Anthems (Box 24)
    - Typescripts (Box 25)
  - Subseries III.3: Please Touch
    Boxes 26 - 32, Files are arranged alphabetically
    - Bach, George R. Aggressiveness (Box 26)
    - Berlin, Jerry (Box 26)
    - Bioenergetics (Box 26)
    - Body Business (Box 26)
    - Business Groups (Box 26)
    - Correspondence (Box 26)
    - Circuit Riders (Box 26)
    - Criticism of Movement (Box 26)
    - Education (Box 26)
    - Encomia (Box 27)
    - Encounter Groups (Box 27)
    - Esalen & Catalogues (Box 27)
    - Followup (Box 27)
    - Foreign Uses of Groups (Box 27)
    - Future of Movement (Box 27)
    - Gibbs, Jack (Box 27)
    - Gestalt - Perls et al. (Box 27)
    - Gustaitis & other writers (Box 27)
    - History (Box 28)
    - HPM People and Mail (Box 28)
    - Human Potential Movement Update (Box 28)
    - Huxley, Aldous (Box 28)
    - Japanese (Box 28)
    - Leaderless Groups (Box 28)
    - Lists of Groups (Box 28)
    - Marathons (Box 28)
    - Maslow, Abraham (Box 28)
    - Moreno, J.L. Psychodrama (Box 28)
    - Murphy, Michael (Box 28)
    - Mysticism (Box 28)
    - National Training Labs (Box 28)
    - Nudity (Box 29)
    - Odd Groups (Box 29)
    - Original Notes (Box 29)
    - Philosophy (Box 29)
    - Reading List (Box 29)
    - Research Notes (Box 29)
    - Racial Groups (Box 29)
    - Rolf, Ida (Box 29)
    - Satir, Virginia (Box 29)
    - Sex Education (Box 29)
    - Sex and Marriage (Box 29)
    - Synanom Chap (Box 29)
    - Tavistock Clinic (Box 29)
    - Weir, John (Box 29)
    - Typescript (Box 30)
    - Alphabetical Files: A-I (Box 31)
    - Mi-Sy (Box 32)
  - Subseries III.4: Margaret Mead: A Life
    Boxes 33 - 44, Files are arranged alphabetically
    - A-Bl (Box 33)
    - Bo-Cu (Box 34)
    - Ek-Freeman's (Box 35)
    - Freedom-La (Box 36)
    - Le-Ne (Box 37)
    - Notes (P. 1-965) (Box 38)
    - Notes (P. 966-1191) No-Re (Box 39)
    - Sa-W (Box 40)
    - Chronological File: 1940's-1978 (Box 41)
    - Typescript Drafts: Chapters 1-12 (Box 42)
    - Typescript Drafts: Chapters 13-22 (Box 43)
    - Typescript Drafts: Chapters 23-End (Box 44)
- Series IV: Miscellaneous Files
  - Folders 1-6 (Box 45)
  - Folders 7-12 (Box 46)
- Series V: Note Cards
  - Card File 1
  - Card File 2
  - Card File 3
  - Card File 4
  - Card File 5
  - Card File 6
- Series VI: 1989 Addition
  - Subseries VI.1: Families
    - M-Re (Box 47)
  - Subseries VI.2: Margaret Mead: A Life
    Boxes 48 - 52
    - Co-Notes (chapter 1-3) (Box 48)
    - Notes (chapter 4-7) - Re (Box 49)
    - T.ms (setting copy for printer) (Box 49)
    - Parts 1-5 (Box 50)
    - Parts 6-8 (Box 51)
    - Photographs for book (Box 52)
- Series VII: Correspondence
  - Subseries VII.1: Cataloged Correspondence
    - Adler, Renata To Jane Howard, New York, NY, 10 October 1976, (t.l.s.) (Box 53)
    - Bellow, Saul To Jane Howard, Israel, June 1970, (2 a.p.c.s.) (Box 53)
    - Berryman, John To Jane Howard, Ireland, 15 March 1967 and June 1970, (1 t.l.s., 1 a.l.s.) (Box 53)
    - Capote, Truman To Scherman, France [?], 1966, (1 a.p.c.s.) (Box 53)
    - Chaplin, Charles To Scherman, Switzerland, 14 April 1964, (1 t.l.s.) (Box 53)
    - Child, Julia To Jane Howard, Cambridge, MA, 21 November 1966, (1 t.l.s.) (Box 53)
    - Close, Glenn To Jane Howard, 28 November 1985, (a.l.s.) (Box 53)
    - Didion, Joan To Jane Howard, [v.d.], (6 a.l.s., 2 t.l.s.) (Box 53)
    - Dorris, Michael To Jane Howard, Cornish, NH, 1 February 1989, (1 t.l.s.) (Box 53)
    - Dunne, John To Jane Howard, [v.d.], (2 a.l.s., 4 t.l.s.) (Box 53)
    - Ford, Betty and Gerald R. To Jane Howard, [n.d.], (1 a.c.s.) (Box 53)
    - Graves, Robert To Jane Howard, Spain, 1 July 1963, (1 a.l.s.) (Box 53)
    - Kosinski, Jerzy To Jane Howard, New York, NY, 23 January 1978, (1 t.l.s.) (Box 53)
    - Lehmann, John To Jane Howard, London, England, 13 May 1964, (1 a.l.s.) (Box 53)
    - Mead, Margaret To [v.p.], [v.p.], [v.d.], (4 t.l.s., 1 signature) (Box 53)
    - Morgenthau, Robert To Jane Howard, New York, NY, [v.d.], (3 t.l.s., 1 a.n.s.) (Box 53)
    - Nabokov, Vera To Jane Howard, [v.p.], [v.d.], (3 t.l.s.) (Box 53)
    - Nabokov, Vladimir To Jane Howard, Paris, France, [n.d.], (1 t.l.s.) (Box 53)
    - Nixon, Pat To Jane Howard, San Clemente, CA, [n.d.], (1 a.l.s.) (Box 53)
    - Osborn, Bob To Jane Howard, Salisbury, CT, March 1965, (1 a.l.s.) (Box 53)
    - Perelman, S.J. To Jane Howard, [v.p.], [v.d.], (3 t.l.s., 1 a.p.c.s.) (Box 53)
      [1 newspaper clipping enclosed]
    - Porter, Katherine Anne To Jane Howard, Washington, D.C., 9 November 1959, (1 t.l.s.) (Box 53)
    - Pound, Ezra To Editor of Life Magazine, Venice, Italy, 2 April 1964, (1 a.l.s.) (Box 53)
    - Rockefeller, Mary To Jane Howard, Albany, NY [?], 31 December 1959, (1 t.l.s.) (Box 53)
    - Roth, Henry To Jane Howard, [v.p.], [v.d.], (4 t.l.s.) (Box 53)
    - Satir, Virginia M. To Jane Howard, Palo Alto, CA, 9 September 1976, (1 t.l.s.) (Box 53)
    - Schippers, Thomas To Jane Howard, Bayreuth, [n.d.], (1 a.p.c.s.) (Box 53)
    - Styron, Rose To Jane Howard, 21 May 1968, (1 a.l.s.) (Box 53)
    - Updike, John To Jane Howard and Dave Scherman, [v.p.], [v.d.], (6 t.p.c.s.) (Box 53)
      [only one card to Dave Scherman, five to J.T.H.]
    - Van Doren, Mark To Jane Howard, Falls Village, CT, 16 December 1955 and 23 August 1959, (1 a.l.s., 1 t.l.s.) (Box 53)
    - Walters, Barbara To Jane Howard, 19 November 1979, (1 t.l.s.) (Box 53)
    - Waugh, Evelyn To Jane Howard, Taunton, 17 September 1964, (1 a.l.s.) (Box 53)
    - Wolfe, Tom To Jane Howard, New York, NY, 2 January 1967, (1 a.l.s.) (Box 53)
  - Subseries VII.2: Arranged (Alphabetically)
    - 50 Plus - DuBois (Box 54)
    - E - Hok (Box 55)
      [Includes letters from Jane Howard to other people in the general "H" file.]
    - Hogbin - Mayhew (Box 56)
    - McGill University - Notre Dame Magazine (Box 57)
    - O - Sadler (Box 58)
    - Sangamon State University - Sterling Lord Agency (Box 59)
    - T - Yale University Press (Box 60)
      [Also includes a folder of miscellaneous correspondence]
  - Subseries VII.3: Arranged (Chronologically)
    1956 - 1970s, Boxes 61 - 67
    - Howard Lipsey and Family Miscellaneous correspondence, 1956 - 1959 [?], (1 Folder ) (Box 61)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1958, (1 Folder ) (Box 61)
    - Roy Riddick Miscellaneous correspondence, 1961, (1 Folder ) (Box 61)
    - "Worth Saving - '60s," Miscellaneous correspondence, 1960s, (1 Folder ) (Box 61)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1960s - 1970s, (1 Folder ) (Box 61)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, [v.p.], 1970 - 71, (1 Folder ) (Box 62)
    - Time, Inc. Miscellaneous correspondence, [v.p.], 1960s - 1970s, (1 Folder ) (Box 62)
    - McWhirter, Bill Miscellaneous correspondence, [v.p.], 1960s, (1 Folder ) (Box 62)
    - Goldstein, Sandoval, others Miscellaneous correspondence, [v.p.], 1966 - 68, (1 Folder ) (Box 62)
    - Goldstein, Tingle Miscellaneous correspondence, [v.p.], 1969, (1 Folder ) (Box 62)
    - "Worth Saving - '70s," Miscellaneous correspondence, [v.p.], 1970s, (1 Folder ) (Box 62)
    - Brownwood, David Miscellaneous correspondence, [v.p.], 1970s, (1 Folder ) (Box 62)
    - "MacDowell People" Miscellaneous correspondence, [v.p.], 1970s, (1 Folder ) (Box 62)
    - Sandoval, Goldstein, others Miscellaneous correspondence, [v.p.], 1972 - 74, (1 Folder ) (Box 62)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, [v.p.], Winter, 1973 - 74, (1 Folder ) (Box 62)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, [v.p.], Spring, 1974, (1 Folder ) (Box 62)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, [v.p.], 1970s, (1 Folder ) (Box 62)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, [v.p.], 1979, (1 Folder ) (Box 62)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, Sag Harbor, [v.p.], 1980, (1 Folder ) (Box 62)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, "To Save", [v.p.], 1981, (1 Folder ) (Box 62)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, [v.p.], 1980s (Box 63)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, [v.p.], 1985 - 87 (Box 64)
      [Also includes some clippings, flyers and miscellaneous items.]
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, [v.p.], 1985 -91 (Box 65)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, [v.p.], 1994 - 95 (Box 66)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, [v.p.], 1994 (Box 67)
  - Subseries VII.4: Arranged (Family)
    1928 - 1960, Boxes 68 - 70
    - Jack Howard Miscellaneous correspondence, 1928 (Box 68)
    - The Howard Family Birth announcement, Miles City, MT, 1935, (1 telegram) (Box 68)
    - The Howard Family Death announcement, Pomona, CA, 1941, (1 telegram) (Box 68)
    - The Howard Family Miscellaneous correspondence, 1938 - 39 (Box 68)
    - From John Harvey Howard Miscellaneous correspondence, World War II (Box 68)
    - The Howard Family Miscellaneous correspondence, 1940s (Box 68)
    - The Howard Family Miscellaneous correspondence, 1949 - 52 (Box 68)
    - The Howard Family Miscellaneous correspondence, 1953 (Box 68)
      [Includes letters from R.P. Howard and Ann C. Howard]
    - The Howard Family Miscellaneous correspondence, 1954 (Box 68)
    - From John Harvey Howard Miscellaneous correspondence, 1954 (Box 68)
    - The Howard Family Miscellaneous correspondence, 1950s (Box 68)
    - From Robert P. Howard Miscellaneous correspondence, 1950s (Box 68)
    - From Jane T. Howard Letters to family from University of Michigan, 1951 - 1954 (Box 68)
    - The Howard Family Miscellaneous correspondence, 1955 (Box 68)
    - The Howard Family Miscellaneous correspondence, 1956 (Box 68)
    - The Howard Family and Friends Miscellaneous correspondence, 1956 (Box 68)
    - The Howard Family Miscellaneous correspondence, 1956 (Box 68)
    - The Howard Family Miscellaneous correspondence, 1957 - 61 (Box 68)
    - John H. and James Howard Miscellaneous correspondence, 1959 (Box 68)
    - The Howard Family and Friends Miscellaneous correspondence, 1960 (Box 68)